A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Administrative Functions, RG 4 FA1798
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Communications, 1943-2017; 2; 9.78 Cubic Feet 28 containers
  - Biographical Files, 1943-2017; 2.2; 2.09 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 1 half document box
    - Biographical Files - Trustees, 1950-2017; 2.2.4
      - Hughes, Chris, 2009-2012 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        News release announcing Chris Hughes' election to the BOT, Knight Foundation. Included is a biographical sketch. Also included are two copies of Fast Company magazine, April 2009, featuring Chris Hughes on the cover and the story about his involvement with the Obama Campaign entitled, "The Kid who made Obama President". Also included is a story from the KF website: "Knight trustee Chris Hughes, new Publisher of The New Republic." Also included is an opinion piece by Dana Milbank appearing in the Washington Post, "The New Republic is dead, thanks to its owner, Chris Hughes" which is critical of Hughes' handling of the venerable magazine and a Wall Street Journal story, "Power Couple Lists Their Soho Condo" about Hughes' Manhattan apartment.
      - Ito, Joi, 2010 March 28-2017 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 4954
        News release announcing Joi Ito's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation. Also included is a photo of Ito and Alberto Ibarguen at Joe's Stone Crab for Rolfe Neill's retirement party. Also included is correspondence between Ito and Ibarguen re: Ito's interest in KF and an article on Ito and biographical information and a memo from Alberto to staff and trustees re: MIT disobedience award.
      - Jinks, Larry, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 258
        Biographical sketch, article and news release re: Knight Foundation trustee, 1992- 1994.
      - Johnson, Tom, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 1874
        Biographical file of Tom Johnson, CNN Chairman and CEO and KF trustee from 1991-1999. Includes several biographical sketches, curriculum vitae, news release, and letters upon his resignation.
      - Knight, James L., 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 259
        Includes memos re: James L. Knight's medical condition, death and funeral; letters of condolence; program for funeral service, with copies of remarks by Lee Hills and Knight's daughters; program for dedication ceremonies for the James L. Knight Physics Building at the University of Miami; biographical sketch; and a tribute to Knight in the Knight-Ridder 1st Quarter Report.
      - Knight, James L., 1991 February 6-March 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 2207
        Articles are on the death of James L. Knight, his life and times, his funeral, and the terms of his will.
      - Knight, John S., 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 260
        Correspondence re: biography of John S. Knight by Charles Whited. Includes contracts with the publisher and author.
      - Knight, John S., 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 261
        Newspaper articles principally concerned with the death of John S. Knight, 6/16/81. Included are articles on his life, the terms of his will and his bequeths, especially to the Knight Foundation, his funeral, and memorials to him.
      - Knight, John S., 1988 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
        Knight File Number - 729
        Charles Whited's biography of John S. Knight, "Knight: A Publisher in the Tumultuous Century," was published in 1988 by the E.P. Dutton Company. Kinght Foundation commissioned the book and holds the copyright. The book details the life of John S. Knight (1894-1981) in 405 pages. Hardcover. Two copies.
      - Knight, John S., 1955-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 2203
        Magazine articles on John S. Knight, including Newsweek (1955), "Knight of the Press: The New Breed in a Tough Game"; Business Week (1970), "Why newspapers are making money again", The Ledger (1998), "Top 50 Most Important Floridians of the 20th Century", and Editor & Publisher (1999), "Most Influential Newspaper People of the 20th Century".
      - Knight, John S., 1975 July 16-2006 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 2204
        Tributes and memorials on the life and death of John S. Knight. Includes the program for the Polsky Humanitarian Award, given to Knight in 1975; several copies of the funeral program; a memorial done by the Akron Regional Development Board; several copies of the program for the dedication of a memorial plaque by the Society of Professional Journalists on the Akron Beacon Journal building; the 1981 Annual Report for the Knight Foundation; and the text of a speech by Bob Giles at the ASNE Convention, April 5, 2001 re: "Leadership Moment: John S. Knight" in which he describes Knight's writing of "Editor's Notebook" and his response to the Vietnam War. Also included are remembrances/anecdotes of Ray Fisher, Miami Herald photographer, about his career at the newspaper. Jack and Jim Knight and Alvah Chapman are briefly mentioned.
      - Knight, John S., 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 2205
        Letters, some with copies of newspaper articles attached, expressing sympathy on the death of John S. Knight. Most of the letters were addressed to C.C. Gibson. Also includes is a 1983 letter from the editor of the Miami Herald enclosing an article on the 20th anniversary of the dedication of the Herald building.
      - Kronick, Susan, 2011 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 4959
        News release announcing Susan Kronick's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation.
      - Maidenberg, Michael, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 1523
        Release and clipping noting Mr. Maidenberg's election to the Board of Trustees. Also included is a biographical sketch of Maidenberg and a copy of a commencement address he delivered to the graduating class of Columbia Graduate School of Journalism, focusing on the flooding of Grand Forks, North Dakota.
      - Mayer, Christine Amer, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 5725
        News release re: election of Christine Amer Mayer, president of the GAR foundation of Akron, as a trustee.
      - McDowell, C. Blake, Sr., 1950-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 2688
        Obituary of C. Blake McDowell, Sr., Knight Foundation founding trustee (1950-1977) and vice-president and former director, secretary and chief counsel for Knight newspaper group.
      - Milburn, Kenneth L., 1973 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 2687
        Obituary of Kenneth L. Milburn, Knight Foundation trustee (1951-1968) and treasurer and former general manager of the Akron Beacon Journal.
      - Neill, Rolfe, 1987-2012 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 2784
        News release announcing Rolfe Neill's reelection to the KF Board of Trustees in 1996. Also includes biographical sketches and news articles. Also included is the program for Rolfe's retirement dinner at Joe's Stone Crab, menu, and guest lists.
      - Nelson, Anna Spangler, 2011 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        Knight File Number - 4956
        News release announcing Anna Spangler Nelson's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation.
      - Noland, Mariam C., 2002-2014 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        Knight File Number - 2785
        Nominating committee report on Mariam C. Noland's election to the KF Board of Trustees; curriculum vitae and biographical sketch. Copy of photo [poor quality - taken with iphone] of Mariam leading a discussion at the KF Media Learning Seminar. Also included is a description of her home, a Saarinen designed house in Grosse Pointe Farms, Michigan.
      - Olson, Beverly Knight, 1987-2012 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        Knight File Number - 2209
        News release on the appointment of Olson to the Knight Board of Trustees. Release has been edited. Included is an article on Olson and her contributions to The Children's Hospital of Georgia. Also includes a news article on Knight's husband, Ed Olson, publisher of the Macon Telegraph. And an article in "The Dell & Cannon", school publication of the Ransom Everglades School in Miami, where Olson, a 1968 graduate of the school, was the 2007 commencement speaker. Also included is a newsletter for Goodwill Industries of Middle Georgia ("Goodwill Connections") featuring a story on the recently opened Knight Resource Center which features a picture of Beverly Olson (not detailed) at the dedication. Also included is a commemorative photo book, "Celebration of Support: University of Georgia" of photos taken at a reception to honor the University of Georgia's Most Loyal Supporters in February 2012. KF was a Celebration of Support 2012 Honoree. Beverly Olson and Beverly Blake attended the event.
      - Ong, John D., 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Knight File Number - 2210
        Biographical sketches, newsclips, newsletters, meeting record (March 1997-December 1999) and tribute for Knight Foundation trustee, John D. Ong, trustee from 1995-2002.
      - Palfrey, John, 2011 October 27-2013 September 10 (Box 2, Folder 16)
        Knight File Number - 4955
        News release announcing John Palfrey's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation. John Palfrey's article, "Building a Digital Public Library of America - the Digital Shift", which mentions Knight Foundation's $1 million grant. Also included is a KF news release announcing Palfrey's election as KF chair elect and a bio as Head of School for the Phillips Academy, Andover, MA, as well as a short email from John to the KF staff sharing his excitement on being elected board chair.
      - Powell, Earl W., 2006 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        Knight File Number - 5229
        Letter from Alberto Ibarguen welcoming Powell to KF.
      - Rodriguez, Reinaldo "Ray", 2010 December (Box 2, Folder 18)
        Knight File Number - 4819
        News release announcing the election of Ray Rodriguez, former President and COO of Univision, to the KF board of trustees.
      - Rogers, John W., Jr., 1999 Feburary-December (Box 2, Folder 19)
        Knight File Number - 2788
        Letter from nominating committee recommending John Rogers for the Board of Directors; draft biographical sketch; news release on Rogers' election; biograghical information and brochures re: Ariel Investments, Rogers' company.
      - Stamps IV., E. Roe, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        Knight File Number - 4643
        Biographical file for Roe Stamps, trustee. Contains annual report from the Ransom Everglades private school in Miami. Pictured are Roe and Penny Stamps, who contributed to the school's capital campaign.
      - Stanford, Henry King, 1992-2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        Knight File Number - 1616
        Biographical file for Henry King Stanford, trustee from 1982 until 1997. File includes a biography, curriculum vitae, notes for Lee Hills on Henry King Standord, and news articles. Also included is an obituary for Dr. Stanford who died on January 1, 2009 at the age of 92.
      - Steiger, Paul E., 2007 October 15-2011 (Box 2, Folder 22)
        Knight File Number - 4206
        Biographical file for Paul E. Steiger, trustee. Consists of a NY Times article re: "Group Plans to Provide Investigative Journalism" in which it was announced that Steiger will head up a non-profit group called Pro Publica, which will provide investigative stories free of charge. Alberto Ibarguen is on the board. Also includes an annual report from the Wing Haven Foundation of Miami. KF was listed as a matching gift sponsor; Dia Steiger (wife of Paul) is Executive Director. Rolfe Neill is a patron.
      - Thomas, Edwin (E..J.), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
        Knight File Number - 730
        Akron Beacon Journal biographical article on Edwin (E.J.) Thomas, "Hometown Boy Makes Good: Akron's Eddie Thomas starts tradition atop Goodyear." Also includes notes, memorial program, and obituaries of Thomas.
      - Toomey, Barbara Knight, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        Knight File Number - 262
        Biographical sketches and article re: Knight Foundation Trustee, 1980-1994, and daughter of James L. Knight.
  - Events, 1991-2016; 2.3; 0.57 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 half document box
    The events documented in this series include the openings of the John S. Knight Center in Akron in 1994; Lee Hills Hall at the University of Missouri School of Journalism in 1995; "Meet Knight Foundation: A Conversation with Officers and Program Directors from Knight Foundation," (1993,1996,1998); Knight Foundation 50thAnniversary dinners (2000-2001).
    - Dedication of John S. Knight Center, 1991 October 13-1994 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 235
      Articles re: the John S. Knight Center in Akron, OH, from the Akron Beacon Journal, Dedication and Open House program, Knightline (Newsletter of the center).
    - Dedication of Lee Hills Hall, 1995 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 236
      Materials from the dedication ceremony of Lee Hills Hall at the University of Missouri School of Journalism in Columbia, MO, on 4/18/95. Included are programs, a special edition of the Columbia Missourian, and a transcript of a question-and-answer session between John Ginn and students. The dedication ceremony also included an announcement by Lee and Tina Hills of a Lee Hills Chair in Free Press Studies.
    - Meet Knight Foundation, 1993 June 15-1998 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
      Knight File Number - 237
      Programs from "Meet Knight Foundation-A Conversation with Officers and Program Directors from Knight Foundation" in Detroit, MI (1993), Walnut Creek, CA (1996), and Grand Forks, ND (1998). (3 folders)
    - Community Dinner/ Georgia Music Hall of Fame, 1999 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 2408
      Program and menu re: Community Dinner at the Georgia Music Hall of Fame in Macon, Georgia. The program lists a Statement of Purpose for the Knight Foundation. [3 copies]
    - 50th Anniversary Dinner, 2000 January-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 2407
      Information re: 50th Anniversary Dinner at the John S. Knight Center in Akron, Ohio. The program lists a Statement of Purpose for the Knight Foundation. Also included are invitations, guest lists (with affiliations), and an Akron Beacon Journal commemorative newspaper insert.
    - Lee Hills Legacy: Journalism, Community, Philanthropy Conference, 2001 April 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 2385
      News release, program and transcripts of remarks on Lee Hills and his legacy. The conference was hosted by the University of Missouri-Columbia. Roundtable discussions and remarks featured Hodding Carter, Larry Jinks, Dave Lawrence, Remer Tyson, and Tina Hills. Included are three biographical sketches of Hills.
    - 50th Anniversary Finale, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 2384
      Program, menu and invitation re: 50th Anniversary Finale reception and dinner at the James L. Knight Center in Miami, held June 11, 2001. The program lists the grants awarded in the Miami/Dade County area to commemorate the Foundation's 50th anniversary. Also included are invitation and attendees lists, staff assignments, and logistical information.
    - Dedication of the Knight Center at Walter Lippmann House, Nieman Foundation, Harvard University, 2004 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 2731
      Program and wrapper (from a chocolate bar) for the dedication of the Knight Center at Walter Lippmann House, which houses the offices of the Nieman Foundation at Harvard University. Hodding Carter made remarks and served on a panel discussion. The program provides information on the Knight Foundation's support of journalism.
    - Florida Grand Opera - Opening Weekend Celebration, 2006 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 4060
      Program features a large color picture of the Knight Brothers, together with a description of KF and the text, "Jack and Jim Knight were devoted to Miami and they believed in the power of community. The Officers, Directors, Patrons and Staff of Florida Grand Opera are proud to be supported by the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation and are grateful for their sponsorship of AIDA."
    - An Evening at Knight Concert Hall, 2006 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 4061
      Program for the KF annual staff and trustee holiday party, featuring a performance by dancer Eva Yerbabuena.
    - Knight Foundation welcomes Zaha Hadid, 2006 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 4062
      Program for a luncheon honoring architect Zaha Hadid. Included a welcome and introduction by Alberto Ibarguen.
    - National Press Foundation: 24th Annual Awards Dinner, 2007 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 4063
      Program features a full-page ad for Knight Foundation's "writing the story of transformation."
    - Miami Dream Dinner Program, 2009 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 4874
      KF was s a supporter of the Washington, DC Martin Luther King, Jr. National Memorial and Albert and Susana Ibarguen were dinner chairs for the Miami event, which saluted President Bill Clinton. (3 copies)
    - Akron Community Dinner to Honor Dr. Austen, 2008 November 25-2009 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 4895
      Planning documents for the event, which also included a board of trustees meeting and private dinner at Rob Briggs' home. Included is an invitation, guest lists, and schedule of events.
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics 20th Anniversary Dinner, 2009 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 4767
      Program and Guests' Seating Assignments.
    - Staff Holiday Beach Party, 2009 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 4649
      Email invitations to the KF annual staff holiday party. This year the party is at the Dune Oceanfront Lounge at the Ritz-Carlton on Key Biscayne.
    - Miami Dinner Program, 2009 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 5623
      Program featuring Trabian Shorters, VP/Communities re: Black Males Engagement initiative.
    - Larger Community Foundations Reception & Dinner, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Knight File Number - 5625
      Program for the dinner at Vizcaya Museum and featured Will Ginsberg, President of The Community Foundation for Greater New Haven.
    - Board of Trustees Dinner Honoring Gerald Austen, 2010 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Knight File Number - 4768
      Program, Attendee list and Guests' Seating Assignments for the Miami, FL event.
    - Board of Trustees Meeting, Charlotte, NC, 2010 September 10-14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Knight File Number - 5624
      Staff logistics schedule, run of show and Dinner activities schedule for the Trustees meeting and community dinner.
    - Staff Gathering, 2010 October 6-8 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Knight File Number - 5626
      Instructions to staff re: retreat logistics.
    - Knight Arts Gala, 2011 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Knight File Number - 5461
      Program for the event, which presented Knight Arts Miami winners, a list of winners, and an art proof of a Knight Arts tote bag given to participants.
    - Knight Arts Site Visit and Macon Arts Luncheon, 2011 February (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Knight File Number - 5628
      Itinerary and Run of Show instructions for the Knights Arts Site Visit and Macon Arts Luncheon featuring Dennis Scholl and Beverly Blake.
    - Board of Trustees Dinner at db bistro moderne, 2011 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Knight File Number - 4892
      Program for the Miami, FL event. Selected KF grantees were invited to attend.
    - BMe Challenge Celebrations, 2011 September 28-October 27 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Knight File Number - 5629
      Materials for BMe [Black Male Engagement] Celebrations in Detroit and Philadelphia include memos and emails re: overview of event and draft run of show, invitations, request for proposal, and a Class of 2011 Philadelphia yearbook.
    - Board of Trustees Meeting, Cambridge, MA, 2011 September 11-12 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Knight File Number - 4944
      Logistics schedule; Run of Show and Dinner program; and Luncheon program, which featured Steven Waldman, Senior Advisor to the Chairman of the FCC as the featured speaker.
    - Community Network Builders Gathering, 2011 November 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Knight File Number - 5462
      Program for the event, which co-sponsored by KF and Grassroots Grantmakers. Also includes participants list and KF costs.
    - Knight Arts Gala, 2010 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Knight File Number - 5627
      Run of Show instructions for the Knights Arts Gala in Miami, which featured Dennis Scholl and Alberto Ibarguen.
    - Knight Philadelphia Arts Gala, 2012 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Knight File Number - 5630
      Draft Run of Show for Arts event which featured Arts Challenge winners and a Random Act of Culture.
    - Board of Trustees Dinner, Miami, FL, 2012 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Knight File Number - 5579
      Program for BOT dinner at Tuyo Restaurant in Miami. Featured speaker was Jonathan Haidt, a social psychologist who spoke on morality.
    - Board of Trustees Reception and Dinner, Philadelphia, PA, 2012 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Knight File Number - 5094
      Invitation (3 copies) and final program of reception and dinner held in conjunction with the Board of Trustees meeting at The Barnes Foundation. Civic leaders were invited. Also included is the detailed Event Manual for the BOT meetings and dinners.
    - Board of Trustees Dinner at Mandarin Oriental, 2013 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Knight File Number - 5145
      Program, schedule, menu, guest list and contract for the Miami, FL event. Selected KF staffers were invited to attend.
    - Walter Isaacson Luncheon, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Knight File Number - 5467
      Run of show and guest list for the lunch and book signing at the Miami Ballroom for author, Walter Isaacson.
    - Detroit Community Dinner with Board of Trustees, 2013 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Knight File Number - 5236
      Program, invitation, schedule, menu, and guest list for the Detroit, MI event which took place at the Detroit Institute of Arts. Selected KF staffers were invited to attend. Speeches by Dennis Scholl and Alberto Ibarguen from the event are in the speech files.
    - Board of Trustees Dinner at Mandarin Oriental, 2014 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 5297
      Copy of invitation for a reception and dinner to honor the service of Rob Briggs, Marjorie Knight Crane, Mariam Noland and Earl Powell, who are retiring from the board. All KF staffers were invited to attend. Also included is the dinner program, and guest list.
    - Community Dinner with Board of Trustees and College Hill Conversation, 2014 September 7-8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 5390
      Dinner program (3 copies), invitation, Run of Show schedule of events, guest bios and pictures for the dinner. Run of Show schedule for trustee tour of Beall's Hill, Macon, schedule/agenda and Run of Show for Macon-College Hill Conversation at Mercer University. Also included is a welcome letter to trustees, a picture of staff/trustee trail run participants, and a menu for the Staff Dinner following the trustee meeting.
    - Knight Arts Challenge South Florida 2014 Winners Reception, 2014 December (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 5898
      Program is a list of the 2014 winners. Information included is Project Name, Award Amount, Recipient, and brief project description.